Honor Thy Father...And Thy Mother BUT HOW ABOUT OUR ENEMY'S
PARENTS? How About His Sweetheart, the Girl We Love?
Broken Lullaby is a drama film directed by Ernst Lubitsch.
A young French soldier in World War I is overcome with guilt when he kills a German soldier who, like himself,
is a musically gifted conscript, each having attended the same musical conservatory in France.
The fact that the incident occurred in war does not assuage his guilt.
He travels to Germany to meet the man's family.
Dr. H. Holderlin, played by Lionel Barrymore.
Paul Renard, played by Phillips Holmes.
Fraulein Elsa, played by Nancy Carroll.
Frau Holderlin, played by Louise Carter.
Herr Walter Schultz, played by Lucien Littlefield.
Walter Holderlin, played by Tom Douglas.
Broken Lullaby (a.k.a.
The Man I Killed) is a 1932 American pre-Code drama film directed by
Ernst Lubitsch and released by Paramount Pictures.
The screenplay by Samson Raphaelson and Ernest Vajda is based on the 1930 play L'homme que j'ai tué by
Maurice Rostand and its 1931 English-language adaptation, The Man I Killed, by Reginald Berkeley.
The tone is emotional.